smsglobal.com 2019-03-27

# Privacy Policy - Shhh | Web SMS, Email SMS & SMS APIs

### Information Collection and Use

SMSGlobal is the sole owner of the information collected on this site www.smsglobal.com. This privacy policy describes how SMS Global collects and uses the personal information you provide on our web site:  [**www.smsglobal.com**](http://www.smsglobal.com/).  It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.  
SMSGlobal collects information under the direction of its customersand has no direct relationship with the individuals whose Personal Information it processes. If you are a customer of one of our customers and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our customer that use our Subscription Service, please contact the customer that you interact with directly. We may transfer Personal Information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our customers.

### Registration

You are free to explore the SMSGlobal Website without providing any Personal Information about yourself.

In order to use SMSGlobal’s Website and products such as MXT, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give their contact information (such as name and email address). This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest.

### Account Activation

We request information from the user on our account activation and credit purchase. Here a user must provide financial information (credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing and credit reference purposes for filling customers’ orders. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to (contact) the user.

### Mobile Applications

In addition to information we collect on our Websites, when you use our Mobile Apps we may also collect your city location, device model and version, device identifier (or “UDID”), OS version, and your SMSGlobal Subscription Service credentials.

### Personal Information

This refers to any information that you voluntarily submit to us and that identifies you personally, including contact information, such as your name, e-mail address, company name, address, phone number, and other information about yourself or your business. Personal Information can also include information about any transactions, both free and paid, that you enter into on the Websites, and information about you that is available on the internet, such as from Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and Google, or publicly available information that we acquire from service providers.  
Personal Information also includes Navigational Information or Payment Information where such information can directly or indirectly identify an individual. Navigational information refers to information about your computer and your visits to this website such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit and pages viewed. Please see the “Navigation Information” section below. Payment information includes We collect and process payment information from you when you subscribe to the Subscription Service, including credit cards numbers and billing information, using third party PCI-compliant service providers. Except for this, we do not collect Sensitive Information from you.

### Updating / Accessing / Amending / Correcting Personally Identifiable Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may deactivate it by making the change on our member information page [or by emailing our Customer Support support@smsglobal.com or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.

### Newsletters

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe, simply click the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email to opt-out of our newsletters

### Service-related Announcements

We will send you service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.  
Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account, write to us at support@smsglobal.com or call +61 3 9095 6245 to close your account.

### Import Contacts

You can import contacts from your Outlook or other email account address book to invite them to become members of our site. We collect the username and password for the email account you wish to import your contacts from and will only use it for that purpose.

### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. SMSGlobal’s website will log people out of a secure session after 2 hours of inactivity by a user.

Other cookies we use are in relation to marketing performance. These cookies, such as Google AdWords, Google Analytics, Hotjar, Facebook, LinkedIn, Outbrain, Twitter and Hubspot help us to understand how users interact with our site, doing so anonymously by placing users completing the same actions into an audience “bucket”. These cookies report back to our systems about the pages users have visited or the actions they have completed. The reason for this is so that we are better equipped to provide a more appropriate marketing strategy for our potential customers. For example, by supporting a popular page with a link straight from the homepage to increase satisfied browsers.

We also utilise remarketing products with the information collected from these cookies. For example, Google allows us to build an anonymous audience list based on a user’s action i.e. visited the site, which we can then use as a target audience to display advertising to across Google’s display network of content websites.

If you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by SMSGlobal, or any other website, you can do this through your browser settings. Either through browsing on the incognito settings or regularly deleting your cookies. The ‘Help’ function within your browser should tell you how you can restrict or block cookies. For information on how to restrict or block cookies on the browser of your mobile phone you will need to refer to your handset manual.

If you’d like more information on cookies, we find the following link very useful:  

### Log Files

We use IP addresses to analyse trends, administer the site, track user’s movement(s), and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.  
For these purposes, we do link this automatically-collected data to Personal Information such as name, email address, address, and phone number.

### Sharing

We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

We use an outside credit card processing company to bill users for services. This company does not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

We partner with other parties to provide specific services. When the user signs up for these services, we will share names or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services.

These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.  
We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website.

### Information About Children

The Websites are not intended for or targeted at children under 16, and we do not knowingly or intentionally collect information about children under 16 If you believe that we have collected information about a child under 16, please contact us at privacy@SMSGlobal.com, so that we may delete the information.

### Customer Testimonials / Comments / Reviews

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our website which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer’s consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial.  If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at support@smsglobal.com.

### Links

This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, SMS Global, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website (www.smsglobal.com).

### Social Media Widgets

Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at support@smsglobal.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### Surveys & Contests

From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user, therefore, has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and address) and demographic information (such as postcode, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.

### Security

This website takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line.

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with industry-standard strong encryption – SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just ‘surfing’.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to your information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy and what they can do to ensure our customers’ information is protected. Finally, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment, behind a locked door.

Users of the SMSGlobal Messaging Service must realise that although SMSGlobal employs high levels of security, no data transmission over the internet can be 100% safe.

Therefore, use of SMSGlobal’s Messaging is at the client’s own risk.

Furthermore, users must be aware that sending messages with SMSGlobal will have a similar level of security and reliability as that of Mobile Phone Networks.

SMSGlobal, its employees and contractors will not be held liable for any loss or damage whatsoever, incurred through the use of SMSGlobal SMS Messaging, including loss of information due to carrier failure, network failure or negligence on the part of SMSGlobal, its employees or contractors.

Please refer to our Terms and Conditions and Disclaimer for more information.

### Legal basis for processing Personal Information (EEA visitors only)

### Notification of Privacy Statement Changes

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### Ask Us About Your Privacy

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact us at [privacy@smsglobal.com](mailto:privacy@smsglobal.com "privacy@smsglobal.com")

96-98 Market Street  
South Melbourne  
Victoria 3205  
Australia

Last reviewed on 25/05/2018
